<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-19T00:26:35-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">untitled</title><subtitle>a mix of basketball, tech, and other things that cross my mind</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Daily: new app in town</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/18/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: new app in town" /><published>2020-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/18/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/18/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;I had a fun time finding some really streets to climb in SF. Without tourists, I even got to go up the wiggly Lombard St. Afterwards I counted the cogs on my cassette and realized it’s an 11-30, which means I still have some room to get gears better for climbing. I never anticipate really ever having to use that though, so I probably won’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&quot;405&quot; width=&quot;590&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/3312111091/embed/425e6d431b283afafc278a055e1e6cdb3d54046b&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a new social app that’s all the rage- Clubhouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s your first look at Clubhouse, the app every VC is talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/xIdqnz8DS8&quot;&gt;https://t.co/xIdqnz8DS8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; joshconstine (@JoshConstine) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JoshConstine/status/1251668138543874048?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 19, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a spontaneuous audio group chat app, and twitter was just bunch of clubhouse takes today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc is back! &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2020/04/18/its-time-to-build/&quot;&gt;Must read&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caught up on a few Stratechery daily updates.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+KeW1PKPsk&quot;&gt;Bet the Process&lt;/a&gt; about the traits behind successful gamblers / advantage players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davie504 is a riot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a70dbulRjx0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engineering!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vtN4tkvcBMA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I had a fun time finding some really streets to climb in SF. Without tourists, I even got to go up the wiggly Lombard St. Afterwards I counted the cogs on my cassette and realized it’s an 11-30, which means I still have some room to get gears better for climbing. I never anticipate really ever having to use that though, so I probably won’t do it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: the days blend together</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/15/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: the days blend together" /><published>2020-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/15/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/15/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m on a lighter week of running / biking this week after three pretty tough weeks. I’ll actually still try to up my run mileage after feeling really good running pretty easy on Monday. I did a steady 5mi @ 7:00 pace today and it never felt too fast, so I was pretty pleased by that. I’m still wary of doing too much faster running, so will probably just chill below 8:00 for the rest of my miles this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy about being productive today, and it’s a really good feeling to be in flow state, just letting irrelevant shit not use up any brain cycles. I wonder if consistency around sleeping / waking up can help with achieving sustained productivity / flow state across days instead of just within days. Everything is just blending together anyways. The internet has become reality. [insert something something Baudrillardian hyperreality]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to the COVID cocaphony again, but this was cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;pretty cool that when you publish the code to your ideas/charts/models, people can easily test new ideas on top of it! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/r1UOw9Ki91&quot;&gt;https://t.co/r1UOw9Ki91&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Canzhi (@canzhiye) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canzhiye/status/1250522541963096064?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 15, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kostya was able to test using deaths data instead of cases data on this kind of novel take trying to estimate real-time rate of transmission by just changing a few lines of code because OP made it public. So much easier to trust data analysis that is reproduceable too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really sad Wired article about Lee Holloway and the effects of FTD on not only him, but his family, friends, and coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+Lv5PFcn0g&quot;&gt;good overview of “advanced” stats in soccer&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been dabbling in doing some predictive modeling for soccer after I stumbled upon some event data and this was an easy to listen to overview of the more popular parts (not cutting edge) of soccer analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got weird recs lol&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZxnBveop5no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m on a lighter week of running / biking this week after three pretty tough weeks. I’ll actually still try to up my run mileage after feeling really good running pretty easy on Monday. I did a steady 5mi @ 7:00 pace today and it never felt too fast, so I was pretty pleased by that. I’m still wary of doing too much faster running, so will probably just chill below 8:00 for the rest of my miles this week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: Last few days</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/11/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: Last few days" /><published>2020-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/11/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/11/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rohanpai.substack.com/p/information-food-for-the-mind&quot;&gt;Rohan and I agreed we’d be writing 3 times / week&lt;/a&gt;. Putting something here everyday seems to induce me to produce just like super low quality stuff (see 3/25 lol).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was my biggest biking week ever - 178 miles and over 12 hours in the saddle. If I do my long run tomorrow (pending how my achilles feel), I’ll have completed 15 hours of cardio this week. If all goes well, it’d be fun to race once that’s a thing again and see the progress. Next week will be a lighter week to make sure I’m not getting too fatigued after three pretty big weeks by my standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/training.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;💯 &lt;br /&gt;weirdest stuff i saw were these effusive articles about how like Vietnam didn’t have covid TWO WEEKS ago. they’re on lockdown now. people writing this stuff &amp;amp; people sharing on here are just trying to score points... &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/JGYv6dStq8&quot;&gt;https://t.co/JGYv6dStq8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; canzhi is at home right now (@canzhiye) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canzhiye/status/1247768604432465923?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 8, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to expand on this take a little bit. It’s never been clearer to me that the media has no interest in searching for truth. They just want to feed the masses; produce lowest common denominator content. A great example of this is the growing genre of “what we can learn from how X handled coronavirus.” We’re so early in understanding anything about covid, the context behind every country is so different, and the quality of data presented as evidence in these articles is so poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These inter-country comparisons really stoke the flames of the incessant online culture wars. People will conflate properties of a country’s political system with how well they’ve allegedly handled coronavirus, and suggest that if the US did a bunch of completely unrelated political things, then coronavirus would be less severe here too. This stuff is either intentionally intellectually dishonest… or people’s brains are completely broken- they’re just out here building their narratives, their personal brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pecanstreet.org/2020/04/covid/&quot;&gt;covid effects where you might not immediately think about&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ribbonfarm.com/2018/03/29/the-key-to-act-two/&quot;&gt;old thing by @vgr but came across for the first time via twitter recently&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely need to stop listening to news podcasts. It’s filling my brain with noise… basically static.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t even like baseball, but any content that Jon Bois produces, I will gladly consume. Voraciously. His new (ongoing) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6pkVu6Kw00M&quot;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; on the Seattle Mariners is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_f6owc3O_gY&amp;amp;list=PLNuxWfBvNtJl6qJhs40VPsxKxgZnFqBoh&quot;&gt;pretty good&lt;/a&gt; (ha ha).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s probably one of the most underrated geniuses of this century. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5oNB6tlSZ2A&amp;amp;list=PLUXSZMIiUfFRSunlJERh9k1RFNnGGhnzG&quot;&gt;His 5-part MMA documentary&lt;/a&gt; examines the relationship between labor, fighting, and our postmodern condition. It has &amp;lt;1M views. Dumb clickbait shit by Buzzfeed has tens of millions of views. Bullshit. People lack taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;misc&quot;&gt;Misc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t really like following national politics, but Bernie dropping out did make me spend a few brain cycles here. After being the favorite post Iowa / New Hampshire / Nevada, he somehow still failed to be recognized as a legit mainstream candidate. &lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+FOOTuytv0&quot;&gt;The Weeds did a good episode&lt;/a&gt; about what’s next and what to take away from his candidacy. If his most vocal supporters are representative at all of his wider support, I’m becoming increasingly concerned that they’ll either sit out the election or vote for Trump. In fact, a second term for Trump definitely adds more to the narrative that running a moderate candidate doesn’t work (Hillary 2016, Biden 2020), whether that’s actually true or not. It almost makes more sense for the hardcore Bernie supporters to just vote for Trump. Anyway, I don’t really add anything to the politics discourse, so I will stop here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a Zwift race for the first time this week! Is this esports? The race is somewhat gamified through powerups, but ultimately, the competitors still have to do the thing they’d do for the actual sport. So maybe not really an esport. Interested in seeing how this evolves!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Rohan and I agreed we’d be writing 3 times / week. Putting something here everyday seems to induce me to produce just like super low quality stuff (see 3/25 lol).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: Empty brain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/07/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: Empty brain" /><published>2020-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/07/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/07/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;My brain has been feeling a bit empty the past week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started doing some freelance iOS work. It’s very nostalgic, given that making apps was how I got started with programming…back in 2009/2010!!! Time really goes too fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without sports, my content consumption patterns have changed a lot. I feel like I’m looking at a lot more normie stuff than I used to. I guess that’s what happens when the thing I actually know a lot about gets taken from me. Maybe it’s time to get deep into something else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have an anon twitter account where I kind of just stream some of my random thoughts to. I like the idea of being anon because my ideas there get judged more for their quality than for who they’re tweeted by. It’s also just an outlet for bursts of kind of hot takes that I don’t want to attach my name to. Maybe that’s problematic lol&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My brain has been feeling a bit empty the past week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: April is the cruelest month, or something</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/01/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: April is the cruelest month, or something" /><published>2020-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/01/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/01/daily.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m doing some contracting for a friend. Cool to be doing iOS work again. Kind of back to my roots. I can’t believe it’s been over 10 years since I first downloaded Xcode and learned to code. Now I get to do much cooler stuff of course :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workout&quot;&gt;Workout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got new running shoes, or really they’re just a new pair of the old shoes I had. Especially in these times, I’ll opt for exploit over explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left as an exercise for the reader&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Work I’m doing some contracting for a friend. Cool to be doing iOS work again. Kind of back to my roots. I can’t believe it’s been over 10 years since I first downloaded Xcode and learned to code. Now I get to do much cooler stuff of course :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: It’s been a few days</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/31/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: It's been a few days" /><published>2020-03-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/31/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/31/daily.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming-calories&quot;&gt;Consuming calories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten to cook a lot more, which is usually tons of fun, but also so easy for me to feel like I’m running out of ideas with a slightly limited set of ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made normal boring stuff like scrambled eggs, pb sandwiches, pasta, burgers, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some of the (weirder) stuff I’ve taken pics of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sous vide chicken thighs in some buns…no veggies, so threw some carrots on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chicken_sandwich.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was okay, but crazy spicy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;what the fuck did i just make &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/aWgyjWpCKs&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/aWgyjWpCKs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; canzhi is at home right now (@canzhiye) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canzhiye/status/1243737841600843778?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 28, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually hate instant coffee, but I went and grabbed some to make this. Was too much effort to whip it up for a mediocre tasting drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;made the dalgona coffee thing &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/LN2TGzCocg&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/LN2TGzCocg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; canzhi is at home right now (@canzhiye) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canzhiye/status/1244331974103142400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 29, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sous vide chicken thighs, with Indian-ish flavors (turmeric, ginger, cumin, salt, pepper). I also don’t know why these images aren’t rotated properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chicken.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Braised red cabbage with onions and apples. Didn’t have any carbs, so I threw it in some tortillas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/red_cabbage.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;burning-calories&quot;&gt;Burning calories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did 130 miles on the bike and 19 miles on my feet last week – probably my biggest week of cardio work in a long time, so I was pretty worn out by Sunday. Silver lining of this corona stuff is I’ll hopefully come out of this in top cardio shape, and maybe I’ll do a couple races. I’ve been running way slower (intentionally) than ever before, but I’m hoping it pays off by keeping me free of weird pains and aches that I’ve gotten before.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Consuming calories</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: Real-world data and some ranting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/27/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: Real-world data and some ranting" /><published>2020-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/27/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/27/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;People love to read too much into dumb headlines. So many people shared the “US surpasses Italy in confirmed coronaviruses cases” news today. Guess what? It’s fucking meaningless! We could’ve looked at the growth rate some days ago and known this was going to happen. Additionally, once again, confirmed cases aren’t a great metric (more below). If I’m going to spend brain cycles on coronavirus, I want to think critically, go beneath the surface, and explore data myself… OR make memes. Not share these normie-ass articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second-order effects of these braindead articles are odd. I’ve even seen it lead to some of my Facebook friends (who are a lost cause by now – they still think this is nothing more than the flu) to proclaim that “WELL ACTUALLY Italy still has more cases per capita.” Wow they must be so smart to know how to divide a number by the population of a country. Many of these people like to talk about how the media is incentivized to spin stories to attract clicks / views, and how because of this we can’t trust the media. In some ways, I share their disdain…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started poking around at some of the different sources of covid related out there. covidtracking.com is really doing a lot of the thankless work around cleaning data from many different sources – very much appreciated. I have a public notebook with some code here:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1qr6G1dxj9I1OlAdxqlZECFQdqfV9RDps&quot;&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1qr6G1dxj9I1OlAdxqlZECFQdqfV9RDps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to find the right questions to ask – they should be answerable from available data, help people get a clearer view of what is actually going on, and not already discussed ad naseum. I’m hesitant to do any forecasting because of lack of domain knowledge, and I certainly don’t want to add more noise to an already incredibly exhausting topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;testing-vs-confirmed-cases&quot;&gt;Testing vs Confirmed cases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a good thread by a buddy on the high correlation between number of tests and confirmed cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;FYI: the growth in positive test results per &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/COVID19Tracking?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@COVID19Tracking&lt;/a&gt; data maps almost 1:1 with the growth in tests performed : R^2 of 0.97. In other words, reporting new and daily case counts is really just reporting on the ramp up in testing capability. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DanRosenheck?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@DanRosenheck&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Noahpinion?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Noahpinion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/T0aZBmVZLm&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/T0aZBmVZLm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kostya Medvedovsky (@kmedved) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kmedved/status/1243612191959453697?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 27, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned from one of the replies that finding R^2 between two time series can lead to spurious correlations though. Curious to see the follow up on this. Or I guess I could do the work myself here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;random-testing&quot;&gt;Random testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;so reading from the source, it&amp;#39;s a bit nuanced.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;5564 tests on &amp;quot;likely&amp;quot; people (prob similar criteria to US). 685 positive. (12%)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;6163 tests on the general population. 52 positive. (0.8%)&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Koeyjk5loP&quot;&gt;https://t.co/Koeyjk5loP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; canzhi is at home right now (@canzhiye) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canzhiye/status/1243642365631287297?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 27, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, Iceland is the only country thus far to do random testing of the general population. They lead the world in tests per 1000 at roughly 30. For comparison, the two highest US states are NY and WA, at 7 and 6 respectively. We have data on Iceland’s randomized tests for 3/20, 3/23, and 3/25 so maybe we can do something with this data. Simple back of the envelope calculation tells us that means there are 2.5M people in the US with the virus if we extrapolate using Iceland’s rate. There’s so many other variables that could render the previous sentence completely inccorect that I almost didn’t want to include it here. Will need to think more about how to best use this data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-on-data&quot;&gt;More on data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of data, the NYT released their county-level coronavirus data. I felt kind of misled by their article though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;this is excellent! can you also release this data? &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SKwAJo8XCT&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/SKwAJo8XCT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; canzhi is at home right now (@canzhiye) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/canzhiye/status/1243636434268897281?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 27, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that county-level data isn’t useful, but seems like getting information about those who actually got the virus would be very useful, or at the very least, interesting to analyze. Perhaps there is county-level demographic and health data that is easily accessible that I could merge with the NYT data… If I remember to go look for it and find it, I’ll add it to the notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking at the testing data from covidtracking.com more closely (with Kostya), I found that the quality was not ideal. There were quite a few days where NY just didn’t report any negative cases… Such is real-world data, I guess. With sports, the data quality is usually much higher. When I’m modeling sports, I feel pretty confident that whatever data is captured is done in a relatively consistent way across games and seasons (still not perfect). It really is a great playground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;masks&quot;&gt;Masks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard conflicting information about the efficacy of masks. The WHO dismisses their usefulness as a protective measure for healthy people, and Michael Osterholm (epidemiologist expert) echoed it on Joe Rogan’s podcast a couple weeks ago. However, I have also seen a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HLrm0pqBN_5bdyysOeoOBX4pt4oFDBhsC_jpblXpNtQ/edit&quot;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; compiling a list of studies that claim that masks are helpful! There’s just so much &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt; on the internet that you will get exactly what you search for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what to believe. Now that the level of seriousness has been ratcheted up, I feel much more aware of how easily misinformation or even half-truths can be spread on social media. This doesn’t feel like the malicious fake news campaigns from the 2016 election, but more an overconfidence in something where the truth is not known. If anyone asks me if masks are effective, I’ll fall back to “I don’t know,” but if I have to go to the grocery store, I’ll take the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pascal%27s_wager&quot;&gt;Pascal’s wager&lt;/a&gt; approach.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">People love to read too much into dumb headlines. So many people shared the “US surpasses Italy in confirmed coronaviruses cases” news today. Guess what? It’s fucking meaningless! We could’ve looked at the growth rate some days ago and known this was going to happen. Additionally, once again, confirmed cases aren’t a great metric (more below). If I’m going to spend brain cycles on coronavirus, I want to think critically, go beneath the surface, and explore data myself… OR make memes. Not share these normie-ass articles.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: cleaning data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/25/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: cleaning data" /><published>2020-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/25/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/25/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time cleaning data today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I spent a lot of time cleaning data today.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: slow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/24/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: slow" /><published>2020-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/24/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/24/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;Ran in the rain today. Did a couple miles a little faster in the middle of the run. Lower calves don’t feel great, so rest of week of running will be much easier / slower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote some code for a little project that will hopefully launch this weekend :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith vs Zach lol &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zachweinberg/status/1242643587243876353&quot;&gt;some of it here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know anything here, so abstaining from commentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Weeds on what to do with industry in times like these. Some comparisons to Ford, factories, etc producing necessary things in WWII. It’s like a car crash - I can’t not pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;misc&quot;&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still looking to take a deeper dive into the covid data. Lack of domain knowledge caveat applies here, but I think I have a few ideas on how I can add something to the discussion without being absolutely destroyed like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aginnt&quot;&gt;@aginnt&lt;/a&gt;. Main thing I want to look at is incorporating testing and demographic data to contextualize the confirmed cases graphs I see everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation around KAT’s mom is really sad. Very brave of him to get in front of a camera and deliver this message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;WE CAN BEAT THIS, BUT THIS IS SERIOUS AND WE NEED TO TAKE EVERY PRECAUTIONS. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/zxMqVB9AWk&quot;&gt;https://t.co/zxMqVB9AWk&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/YouTube?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Karl-Anthony Towns (@KarlTowns) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KarlTowns/status/1242688948335456256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 25, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ran in the rain today. Did a couple miles a little faster in the middle of the run. Lower calves don’t feel great, so rest of week of running will be much easier / slower.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily: untitled</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/23/daily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily: untitled" /><published>2020-03-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/23/daily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/23/daily.html">&lt;p&gt;Does the wildlife come out when humans retreat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&quot;405&quot; width=&quot;590&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/3210311685/embed/6420d55cd2d54ca5d2b0075687290cb417ef0512&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read some stuff about multi-armed bandits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffma/status/1242246589395001351&quot;&gt;Bet the Process&lt;/a&gt; episode recorded at Sloan came out today. Interviews with Ted Knutson and Jeff Yass were both insightful. Knutson was pretty negative about the prospects of a thriving regulated &amp;amp; legalized betting market in the US. Or more specifically it’d only be for recreational bettors. Yass talked about how at SIG they teach all the new traders to play poker first to learn about variance and process-oriented decision making. I think that’s really cool! I’m not good at poker, but those aspects of the game appeal to me as well. Playing games with a mix of luck and skill is way more fun than a game like chess, which is a perfect information all skill game. Actually, not only is it way more fun, it is a much more realistic representation of the real world where we never have perfect information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More multi-armed bandit stuff. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kY-BCNHd_dM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;misc&quot;&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spent some time on Indiehackers today. Exploring ideas to hack on!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Does the wildlife come out when humans retreat?</summary></entry></feed>